<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Josh’s Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-01T20:55:56+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Josh Asch]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Made a Thing - EmojiBoard]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/12/29/i-made-a-thing-emojiboard/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-29T13:23:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/12/29/i-made-a-thing-emojiboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like to use Emoji symbols when I&rsquo;m using my iPhone or iPad, but I don&rsquo;t like having to keep the Emoji keyboard turned on. I always end up hitting the &lsquo;change keyboard&rsquo; button by accident. I set up a few text shortcuts to the symbols I use the most, but there&rsquo;s no easy way to access the other symbols. So I made one. <!-- more --></p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2013/12/29/i-made-a-thing-emojiboard/EmojiBoard.png" width="320" height="568" /></p>

<p>I call it EmojiBoard. It&rsquo;s a web app which lists all the Emoji symbols that work on iOS, allowing them to be copied for use in any app. It&rsquo;s laid out in the exact same way as the Emoji keyboard to make it easy to find certain symbols, and there&rsquo;s a recents section at the top which collects the 21 most recent symbols you&rsquo;ve used.</p>

<p>It works best on iPhone and iPad, and will probably work on Android, but doesn&rsquo;t work on desktop, since it relies on touch.</p>

<p>The web app itself can be found at <a href="http://josh-asch.net/emoji/">josh-asch.net/emoji</a>, and it&rsquo;s open source, so the source can be found <a href="http://github.com/jobbogamer/EmojiBoard">on GitHub</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disable Automatic Emoji in Messages on Mavericks]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/12/27/disable-automatic-emoji-in-messages-on-mavericks/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-27T12:46:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/12/27/disable-automatic-emoji-in-messages-on-mavericks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version 8.0 of Messages.app, shipped with OS X Mavericks, has a new feature which automatically inserts Emoji symbols when you type common text emoticons, such as replacing &ldquo;:)&rdquo; with a smiling Emoji face.</p>

<p>Personally, I prefer to send the actual text rather than an Emoji symbol, but I couldn&rsquo;t find anywhere in the app&rsquo;s preferences to turn it off. After a lot of searching, it turns out the answer is simple. Just click in the text field in Messages and deselect <strong>Edit → Substitutions → Emoji</strong> <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, and emoticons will no longer be replaced with Emoji symbols.</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2013/12/27/disable-automatic-emoji-in-messages-on-mavericks/Disable-Emoji.png" alt="Disable Emoji" /></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>You can also right click in the text field and deselect <strong>Substitutions → Emoji</strong>.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Access iTunes Radio Outside the US]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/10/20/access-itunes-radio-outside-the-us/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-20T22:23:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/10/20/access-itunes-radio-outside-the-us</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the release of iOS 7, Apple introduced <a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/itunes-radio/">iTunes Radio</a>, a service similar to Stations in Rdio or Spotify Radio. Unfortunately, iTunes Radio is only available in the US at the moment – although <a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2013/10/07/apple-to-expand-itunes-radio-to-u-k-canada-australia-new-zealand-and-more-by-early-2014/">rumour has it</a> that the service will be expanding to other countries, including the UK, by early 2014.</p>

<p>However, it&rsquo;s fairly easy to access iTunes Radio now from any country. All you need to do is set up a US iTunes account and log in to that account on the device you want to use to access iTunes Radio. If you don&rsquo;t already have a US iTunes account, follow <a href="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/create-itunes-account-access-usonly-contents-credit-card/">these steps</a> to get one set up without having to enter credit card information.</p>

<p>Once you have a US iTunes account, log in to it from the iTunes store and then return to the Music app on iOS or the library screen in iTunes desktop and you should see a new Radio tab. That&rsquo;s it! You have access to iTunes Radio.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep iTunes OCD at Bay With MetaZ]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/04/11/itunes-ocd-metaz/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-11T23:17:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2013/04/11/itunes-ocd-metaz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re anything like me, you like your iTunes library to look neat and tidy, and to contain all the information it&rsquo;s supposed to, even if your content didn&rsquo;t come from the iTunes Store. For instance, in iTunes 11, the Description field for movies and TV shows became much more prominent. So prominent, in fact, that it purposefully points out that the description is missing if you haven&rsquo;t added one.</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2013/04/11/itunes-ocd-metaz/No-Description-Available.png" alt="No Description Available" /></p>

<p>Short of describing movies and episodes of TV shows yourself in 256 characters, there&rsquo;s no way to consistently add the Description in. That is, unless you use <a href="http://griff.github.io/metaz/">MetaZ</a>. <!-- more --> MetaZ is a new implementation of MetaX, a tagging program which stopped getting updated a while back. It allows you to load in any video file and update its MP4 metadata, which iTunes can then read and display.</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2013/04/11/itunes-ocd-metaz/MetaZ-Main-Window.png" alt="MetaZ Main Window" /></p>

<p>Using MetaZ, metadata fields that aren&rsquo;t editable in iTunes can be edited and saved. For example, the Date field cannot be set in the Get Info panel in iTunes, but shows up when set:</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2013/04/11/itunes-ocd-metaz/Episode-Dates.png" alt="Episode Dates" /></p>

<p>You might be thinking, &ldquo;Great, now there&rsquo;s <em>even more</em> data I need to find so that my iTunes metadata is complete!&rdquo;, and you&rsquo;d be right. However, I haven&rsquo;t mentioned the best feature of MetaZ. After importing a video file, MetaZ will automatically search <a href="http://www.tagchimp.com">Tag Chimp</a>, <a href="http://www.themoviedb.org">TMDb</a> and <a href="http://thetvdb.com">The TVDb</a> to find the appropriate data for that file, including description, date and more. Simply select a file in the right-hand pane, then once MetaZ has finished searching, choose a metadata source in the left-hand pane. The middle pane will then update with the data from your chosen source. Select the checkbox next to each item you wish to save. You can also manually make changes in the text fields if you want.</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2013/04/11/itunes-ocd-metaz/MetaZ-Loaded-Metadata.png" alt="MetaZ Loaded Metadata" /></p>

<p>When you are finished editing, click Write in the toolbar and the metadata will be saved into the file. Once MetaZ has finished writing, iTunes should be updated automatically with the new data. I&rsquo;ve shown the process here with a TV show episode, but the same applies for movies as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Win at Letterpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/12/23/how-to-win-at-letterpress/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/12/23/how-to-win-at-letterpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/letterpress-word-game/id526619424?mt=8&amp;at=10l7rn">Letterpress</a> is the fun new word game from Loren Brichter, of Tweetie fame. Since you&rsquo;ve probably played the game before I won&rsquo;t go into details about the game itself (you could always go to the <a href="http://www.atebits.com/letterpress/">Letterpress page</a>). Disclaimer: These are just some handy tips to help you do better when playing Letterpress. I can&rsquo;t guarantee you&rsquo;ll win more games than you did before. <!-- more --></p>

<h3>Play the longest possible variant</h3>

<p>The rules state that you can&rsquo;t play a word which is at the start of another word that has already been played. For example, if someone plays <strong>photograph</strong>, no one can play <strong>photo</strong>. However, you <em>are</em> allowed to extend previously played words. If <strong>photo</strong> is played first, then <strong>photograph</strong> is still allowed. Because extending words is allowed, your opponent can easily steal tiles back from you by adding one or two letters to the end of your word. If you play <strong>dolphin</strong> and there&rsquo;s an S tile on the board, your opponent can take all the tiles you just won by playing <strong>dolphins</strong>. To combat this, always try to play the longest version of the word that&rsquo;s possible. Add <strong>S</strong> or <strong>ING</strong> to the end of your word to make sure it can&rsquo;t be extended any further. Of course, this isn&rsquo;t foolproof, since if you play <strong>players</strong> it&rsquo;s still possible to play <strong>played</strong> afterwards, which steals most of the tiles you just used.</p>

<h3>Remember the &ldquo;cheating&rdquo; words from Scrabble</h3>

<p>Letterpress seems to use a similar dictionary to Scrabble, so it lets you have the two-letter words some people consider &ldquo;cheating&rdquo;: <strong>qi</strong> <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> for when there&rsquo;s a Q but no U, and <strong>za</strong> <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> for when you can&rsquo;t remember any other words containing a Z. Obviously these words don&rsquo;t score you many blue tiles so use them only when you&rsquo;re desperate for a word with an obscure letter.</p>

<h3>Don&rsquo;t forget about your own tiles</h3>

<p>It can be very easy to focus only on stealing red and grey tiles, and forget that you&rsquo;re allowed to use your own blue tiles to create words. You won&rsquo;t gain any points for using blue tiles, but it might make finding a good word a bit easier.</p>

<h3>Play for territory</h3>

<p>Since you need to own the most tiles to win the game, protect the ones you own by surrounding them on all sides. The best way to do this is to start in one corner and work outwards. Here&rsquo;s an example of what I mean, starting from the lower right corner:</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2012/12/23/Letterpress-Territory-Example.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Playing this way might not keep the most important letters protected (if there is only one E, for example, you&rsquo;d probably want to grab that early on), but it means you most likely have more tiles protected than your opponent.</p>

<h3>Have fun</h3>

<p>Don&rsquo;t forget, the whole point of Letterpress is to enjoy the time you spend playing it. There&rsquo;s no reason to even be competitive. You and a friend could just try and find all the words on the grid with a certain theme. <a href="https://twitter.com/jobbogamer/status/282226813567131648">https://twitter.com/jobbogamer/status/282226813567131648</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><strong>qi</strong>: (of Chinese origin) vital energy believed to circulate round the body in currents<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><strong>za</strong>: (Americanism) slang for pizza<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Longer Passcode on iOS Devices]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/12/11/longer-passcode-on-ios/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T21:15:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/12/11/longer-passcode-on-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Use a passcode to keep your iPhone or iPad safe, but think four digit codes aren’t long enough? Since iOS 5, there has been an option to swap the 4-digit numerical passcode for an arbitrary length alphanumeric one. To set up a longer passcode, open Settings then select General → Passcode Lock. Now turn the Simple Passcode switch to the Off position.</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2012/12/11/longer-passcode-on-ios/Passcode-Lock-Settings.png" width="320" height="480" /></p>

<p>You’ll be prompted to enter your current passcode (if you have one), and then to enter your new passcode. With Simple Passcode turned off, you can enter either numbers, letters or both. However, if you only use numbers in your new passcode, you’ll still be given the numerical keyboard on the lock screen.</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2012/12/11/longer-passcode-on-ios/Long-Passcode-Lock-Screen.png" width="320" height="480" /></p>

<p>You can also add letters to the passcode, but the regular iOS keyboard will show up on the lock screen instead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use a Phone Number for iMessage on iPad and iPod Touch]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/09/21/using-a-phone-number-for-imessage-and-facetime/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T16:43:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/09/21/using-a-phone-number-for-imessage-and-facetime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the main features of iOS 6 on the iPad and iPod touch is the ability to use a phone number for iMessage and FaceTime. Unfortunately it’s not the most intuitive thing to set up. <!-- more --></p>

<h3>What you need</h3>

<ul>
<li>An iPhone running iOS 6 or later</li>
<li>An iPad or iPod touch running iOS 6 or later</li>
<li>An Apple ID set up to use iMessage</li>
</ul>


<h3>Method</h3>

<ol>
<li><p> Turn iMessage off on your iPhone. Open <strong>Settings → Messages</strong> and slide the <strong>iMessage</strong> switch to the <strong>off</strong> position.</p></li>
<li><p> Turn iMessage back on by sliding the switch back to the <strong>on</strong> position.</p></li>
<li><p> Turn off iMessage on your iPad or iPod. This can be done in the same way as on the iPhone. If you don’t see a switch labelled iMessage, you should see your Apple ID’s email address. Tap this and then tap <strong>Sign Out</strong> from the menu.</p></li>
<li><p> Turn iMessage back on on your iPad or iPod. If the switch isn’t there, either tap <strong>Use your Apple ID for iMessage</strong> or enter your password, depending on what you can see.</p></li>
<li><p> You should see a notification such as, “+44 7700 123456 was added to iMessage on the iPhone ‘Mr iPhone’”. You will then be asked if you want to use this number for iMessage and FaceTime on the device you’re using. Tap <strong>yes</strong> and iMessage and FaceTime will be set up with your phone number.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Force Reset and Shutdown iOS Devices]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/06/21/how-to-force-reset-and-shutdown-ios-devices/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-21T12:50:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/06/21/how-to-force-reset-and-shutdown-ios-devices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is your iPhone, iPod touch or iPad having problems and needs to be restarted? Read on to find out how to force your device to either restart or just shut down. <!-- more --></p>

<h3>Restarting</h3>

<p>To force a device to restart, hold down both the Sleep/Wake and Home buttons together. The screen will turn black, then the Apple logo will appear, at which point you can let go of the buttons.</p>

<h3>Shutting down</h3>

<p>If you need the device just to shut down and not turn back on, follow the above steps, but once the Apple logo appears, only let go of the Home button and keep holding the Sleep/Wake button <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>It&rsquo;s nice if, say, you leave your iPod touch in your pocket, it goes through the washing machine and you need to turn it off but the touch screen has stopped working. Yes, that&rsquo;s a true story.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recover iTunes' Missing "Create MP3 Version"]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2011/08/16/recover-itunes-missing-create-mp3-version/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-16T12:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2011/08/16/recover-itunes-missing-create-mp3-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Around the time version 10 was released, the option in iTunes to &ldquo;Create MP3 Version&rdquo; seemingly disappeared for a lot of people. It turns out, it hasn&rsquo;t been removed from iTunes, but there&rsquo;s a setting you need to change to get it back. <!-- more --></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve never changed any settings in iTunes, it&rsquo;s likely the option you&rsquo;ll see if you right-click a track is &ldquo;Create AAC Version&rdquo;. AAC is a great alternative to MP3, since it generally gives better quality, but it&rsquo;s useless for burning MP3 CDs, since you can&rsquo;t burn an AAC track to an MP3 disc. If you try to burn a disc using iTunes and select &ldquo;MP3 CD&rdquo; you&rsquo;ll get this message:</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2011/08/16/recover-itunes-missing-create-mp3-version/cant_burn.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>What you need to do is convert those files to MP3 format. However, in order to do that, you need to get back the &ldquo;Create MP3 Version&rdquo; option. Here&rsquo;s how:</p>

<ol>
<li> Open the iTunes Preferences and then open the General tab of the preferences.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2011/08/16/recover-itunes-missing-create-mp3-version/general_preferences.png" alt="" /></p>

<ol>
<li> Near the bottom is an option which starts &ldquo;When you insert a CD:&rdquo;. To the right of that is a button labelled &ldquo;Import Settings…&rdquo; – click that, and another window will open.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2011/08/16/recover-itunes-missing-create-mp3-version/import_settings.png" alt="" /></p>

<ol>
<li><p> At the top is a drop down labelled &ldquo;Import Using:&rdquo;. Change that drop down to the &ldquo;MP3 Encoder&rdquo; option. Click OK on both windows and you&rsquo;re all set to convert tracks to MP3.</p></li>
<li><p> To convert a track to MP3 format, right-click it and choose &ldquo;Create MP3 Version&rdquo;. iTunes will create a second copy of the track in MP3 format.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Once all the tracks you want to burn are in MP3 format, you&rsquo;ll be able to burn an MP3 disc just fine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remap the Dashboard Key to Launchpad]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2011/07/22/remap-the-dashboard-key-to-launchpad/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-22T12:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2011/07/22/remap-the-dashboard-key-to-launchpad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Lion, Dashboard is given its own space, which is easily opened with a swipe. That means (to me, anyway) that the Dashboard key on the keyboard (F4) is useless. So I remapped it to open Launchpad. <!-- more --></p>

<h3>What you&rsquo;ll need</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong><a href="http://kevingessner.com/software/functionflip/">FunctionFlip</a></strong> by Kevin Gessner &ndash; this allows you to disable the special function of specific function keys.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/os-x-lion/id444303913?mt=12&amp;at=10l7rn">OS X Lion</a></strong> – because, you know, Launchpad is a feature of Lion.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Method</h3>

<ol>
<li> First off, you&rsquo;ll need to <a href="http://kevingessner.com/software/functionflip/">download</a> and install FunctionFlip. It&rsquo;s a preference pane, so you&rsquo;ll be able to access it from System Preferences in the future.</li>
<li> Once it&rsquo;s installed, open it up in System Preferences (it should open automatically once it&rsquo;s installed). In the drop down list on the right, select the keyboard you&rsquo;d like to remap the key on.</li>
<li> Now find Dashboard in the left-hand panel. It should be the fourth in the list. Check the box next to it, which will disable the special function of the key (Dashboard) and turn it into a regular F4 key.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2011/07/22/remap-the-dashboard-key-to-launchpad/functionflip.png" alt="" />
  4. Now click Show All at the top of System Preferences and navigate to the Keyboard preference pane. Open up the Keyboard Shortcuts tab once you&rsquo;re in there.</p>

<ol>
<li> In the left-hand side of that tab, click on Launchpad &amp; Dock. Now select Show Launchpad on the right-hand side. Double-click to the right of the selected row to edit the shortcut, then press F4 on your keyboard. That&rsquo;s it! Pressing the F4 key should now show Launchpad!</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2011/07/22/remap-the-dashboard-key-to-launchpad/shortcuts.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>This is especially useful for those of us with a Magic Mouse, since the mouse doesn&rsquo;t have a gesture for showing Launchpad.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
