<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Games | Josh’s Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/blog/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-01T23:42:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Josh Asch]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Win at Letterpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/12/23/how-to-win-at-letterpress/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jobbogamer.github.io/2012/12/23/how-to-win-at-letterpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/letterpress-word-game/id526619424?mt=8&amp;at=10l7rn">Letterpress</a> is the fun new word game from Loren Brichter, of Tweetie fame. Since you&rsquo;ve probably played the game before I won&rsquo;t go into details about the game itself (you could always go to the <a href="http://www.atebits.com/letterpress/">Letterpress page</a>). Disclaimer: These are just some handy tips to help you do better when playing Letterpress. I can&rsquo;t guarantee you&rsquo;ll win more games than you did before. <!-- more --></p>

<h3>Play the longest possible variant</h3>

<p>The rules state that you can&rsquo;t play a word which is at the start of another word that has already been played. For example, if someone plays <strong>photograph</strong>, no one can play <strong>photo</strong>. However, you <em>are</em> allowed to extend previously played words. If <strong>photo</strong> is played first, then <strong>photograph</strong> is still allowed. Because extending words is allowed, your opponent can easily steal tiles back from you by adding one or two letters to the end of your word. If you play <strong>dolphin</strong> and there&rsquo;s an S tile on the board, your opponent can take all the tiles you just won by playing <strong>dolphins</strong>. To combat this, always try to play the longest version of the word that&rsquo;s possible. Add <strong>S</strong> or <strong>ING</strong> to the end of your word to make sure it can&rsquo;t be extended any further. Of course, this isn&rsquo;t foolproof, since if you play <strong>players</strong> it&rsquo;s still possible to play <strong>played</strong> afterwards, which steals most of the tiles you just used.</p>

<h3>Remember the &ldquo;cheating&rdquo; words from Scrabble</h3>

<p>Letterpress seems to use a similar dictionary to Scrabble, so it lets you have the two-letter words some people consider &ldquo;cheating&rdquo;: <strong>qi</strong> <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> for when there&rsquo;s a Q but no U, and <strong>za</strong> <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> for when you can&rsquo;t remember any other words containing a Z. Obviously these words don&rsquo;t score you many blue tiles so use them only when you&rsquo;re desperate for a word with an obscure letter.</p>

<h3>Don&rsquo;t forget about your own tiles</h3>

<p>It can be very easy to focus only on stealing red and grey tiles, and forget that you&rsquo;re allowed to use your own blue tiles to create words. You won&rsquo;t gain any points for using blue tiles, but it might make finding a good word a bit easier.</p>

<h3>Play for territory</h3>

<p>Since you need to own the most tiles to win the game, protect the ones you own by surrounding them on all sides. The best way to do this is to start in one corner and work outwards. Here&rsquo;s an example of what I mean, starting from the lower right corner:</p>

<p><img src="http://jobbogamer.github.io/images/2012/12/23/Letterpress-Territory-Example.png" width="640" height="320" /></p>

<p>Playing this way might not keep the most important letters protected (if there is only one E, for example, you&rsquo;d probably want to grab that early on), but it means you most likely have more tiles protected than your opponent.</p>

<h3>Have fun</h3>

<p>Don&rsquo;t forget, the whole point of Letterpress is to enjoy the time you spend playing it. There&rsquo;s no reason to even be competitive. You and a friend could just try and find all the words on the grid with a certain theme. <a href="https://twitter.com/jobbogamer/status/282226813567131648">https://twitter.com/jobbogamer/status/282226813567131648</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><strong>qi</strong>: (of Chinese origin) vital energy believed to circulate round the body in currents<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><strong>za</strong>: (Americanism) slang for pizza<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
